(317) 438-0924

Crsschwalm@gmail.com <a>

linkedin.com/in/CarsonSchwalm in

Crsschwalm.github.io

I am a Senior Software Engineer with 4 years of professional experience. My career focus is on the Full Stack of Web Development. I try to prioritize User Experience as well as Clean Code while working on Agile teams. I strive to solve problems in interesting ways and continually iterate on my own skill set!

Technical Skills

App Dev

- TypeScript, JavaScript, ES6, React Native
- NodeJS Express, Sails, Koa, Hapi, etc.
- HTML, CSS, and CSS in JavaScript
- React / Vue with Server Side Rendering
 - Next, Nuxt, Razzle, Gatsby Frameworks
- Webpack, Grunt, Gulp
- Jest, Enzyme

Data & Tooling

- SQL, GraphQL, and CMS
- Elastic Search
- Message Queues & Caching Layers
- Git: CLI & GitHub
- Heroku, Netlify, Expo, AWS
- **Google Analytics**

Professional Experience

02/2017 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer / DMI - Carmel, IN

I have held the role of Technical Lead on various client projects including Lilly.com, LillyTrialGuide.com, Blog.LillyTrialguide.com as well as internally facing web applications. I also have been a key contributor to legacy application rewrites, shared Node modules, and web/native applications. Communicating with client stakeholders, mentoring junior developers, and writing & reviewing code is just part of my daily routine. As a Senior Software Engineer, I see it as my responsibility to seek out effective solutions, engage with team members, and see projects succeed.

06/2016 - 01/2017

Technology Analyst / Virtusa - Indianapolis, IN

In this role, I developed highly customized SharePoint Office 365 intranet sites. As a member of an Agile development team, I took part in iterative releases as well as the full development cycle of user stories. Here I was able to leverage new development pipelines and realize my interests in Application Development.

Education

MAY 2016

BS: Informatics / Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Major GPA: 3.91 **Cumulative GPA: 3.41**

Minors: Business, Computer Science, and Information Technology

Dean's List: 2014-2015

Certifications: Currently training to receive the "AWS Certified Developer – Associate" Certification.